You are not welcome here.
District 9 is a science fiction film directed by Neill Blomkamp.
Thirty years ago, aliens arrive on Earth.
Not to conquer or give aid, but to find refuge from their dying planet.
Separated from humans in a South African area called District 9, the aliens are managed by Multi-National United,
which is unconcerned with the aliens' welfare but will do anything to master their advanced technology.
When a company field agent contracts a mysterious virus that begins to alter
his DNA, there is only one place he can hide: District 9.
Wikus van de Merwe, played by Sharlto Copley.
Christopher Johnson / Grey Bradnam / Trent, played by Jason Cope.
Sarah Livingstone - Sociologist, played by Nathalie Boltt.
Dr Katrina McKenzie, played by Sylvaine Strike.
Interviewee, played by Elizabeth Mkandawie.
Les Feldman - MIL Engineer, played by John Sumner.
District 9 is a 2009 science fiction action film
directed and co-written by Neill Blomkamp.
It was a co-production of New Zealand, the United States, and South Africa.
The film stars Sharlto Copley, Jason Cope, and David James, and was
adapted from Blomkamp's 2005 short film Alive in Joburg.
The film is partially presented in a mock documentary format by featuring
fictional interviews, news footage, and video from surveillance cameras.
The story, which explores themes of humanity, xenophobia and social segregation, begins in an
alternate 1982, when an alien spaceship appears over Johannesburg, South Africa.
When a population of sick and malnourished insectoid aliens is discovered on the ship, the
South African government confines them to an internment camp called District 9.
The title and premise of District 9 were inspired by events in
Cape Town's District Six, during the apartheid era.
District 9 premiered on 23 July 2009 at San Diego Comic-Con, and was released in New Zealand on 13
August, the United States on 14 August and South Africa on 28 August, by TriStar Pictures.
It received positive reviews from critics, and was a financial
success, earning $211 million on a budget of $30 million.
It garnered numerous award nominations, including Academy Awards for Best Picture,
Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Visual Effects, and Best Film Editing.
The film explores themes of street gang, government, genetics, slum, mutation.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.